Guide to the Collection of musical autographs,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series V: Scores
  - Wagner, Richard "Lohengrin," Act I Finale. Parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (32 parts a.ms. fair copy, 1 cover) (Box 37, Folder 373)
  - Wagner, Richard "Lohengrin" Act I Finale. Vocal score., Novello, Ewer, and Co., [n.d.], (1 vol. bd.) (Box 37, Folder 374)
  - Wagner, Richard "Der Fliegende Hollander." Parts for orchestra. Druck: Leipzig; Furstner: Berlin, [n.d.], (41 parts, 12 parts a.ms. fair copy, 1 cover) (Box 37, Folder 375)
  - Wagner, Richard "Parsifal." Score and parts for orchestra. Schott's Sohne: Mainz, 11 June 1870, (44 pages bd., 39 part) (Box 37, Folder 376)
  - Wagner, Richard "Lied an den Abendstern." Score and parts for orchestra., Furstner: Berlin, [n.d.], (12 pages bd. a.ms. fair copy, 31 parts, 3 parts a.ms.) (Box 37, Folder 377)
  - Wagner, Richard "Trauermusik fur Erinnerung au C.M. von Weber." Parts for orchestra. [n.d.], (24 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 38, Folder 378)
  - Wagner, Richard "Eine Faust Ouverture." Score and parts., Breitkopf & Hartel: Leipzig, [n.d.], (37 parts, 3 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 38, Folder 379)
  - Wagner, Richard "Grosser Fest-Marsch." Score, piano score, and parts for orchestra. Schirmer: New York and Schott's Sohne: Mainz, [n.d.], (47 pages bd., 21 pages bd., 46 parts) (Box 38, Folder 380)
  - Wagner, Richard "Tannhauser March," Act II. Score and parts for orchestra., Durand: Paris, [n.d.], (25 pages bd., 33 parts) (Box 38, Folder 381)
  - Wagner, Richard "Die Meistersinger von Nurnberg" Overture. Piano score and parts. Schott's Sohnen: Mainz, [n.d.], (41 parts, 3 parts a.ms. fair copy, 4 parts photocopies) (Box 38, Folder 382)
  - Wagner, Richard "Parsifal." Score and parts for orchestra. Schott's Sohne: Mainz; Breitkopf & Hartel: New York, [n.d.], (17 pages bd., 36 parts) (Box 38, Folder 383)
  - Wagner, Richard "Tannhauser" Overture. Score and parts for orchestra., Furstner: Berlin, [n.d.], (40 pages bd., 42 parts) (Box 38, Folder 384)
  - Wagner, Richard "Die Meistersinger," Act II, Scene III. Score and parts for orchestra. [n.d.], (26 parts a.ms.) (Box 38, Folder 385)
  - Wagner, Richard "Parsifal: Schluss des III Aufzuges." Parts for orchestra., Schott's Sohne: Mainz, [n.d.], (50 parts) (Box 38, Folder 386)
  - Wagner, Richard "Lohengrin: Bridal Chorus," Act III, Scene 1. Score and parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (57 pages bd., a.ms. fair copy, 41 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 38, Folder 387)
    [Some parts include printed sections adhered to a.ms. Housed in two folders.]
  - Wagner, Richard "Parsifal" Overture. Score and parts for orchestra., Schott's Sohne: Mainz, [n.d.], (15 pages bd., 48 parts, 1 part a.ms. fair copy) (Box 38, Folder 388)
  - Wagner, Richard "Der Fliegende Hollander." Parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (30 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 38, Folder 389)
  - Wagner, Richard "Das Rheingold Selection." Score and parts for orchestra. Schott's Sohne: Mainz, [n.d.], (74 pages bd. 45 parts, 20 pages a.ms. fair copy) (Box 38, Folder 390)
    [Harp score handprinted. Housed in two folders.]
  - Wagner, Richard "Tristan und Isolde", Breitkopf & Hartel: Leipzig, [n.d.], (7 pages bd., 46 parts, 1 part a.ms. fair copy) (Box 39, Folder 391)
  - Wagner, Richard "Leibesnacht." Parts for orchestra. [n.d.], (42 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 39, Folder 392)
  - Weber-Weingartner "Invitation to the Dance." Score and parts for orchestra., Furstner: Berlin, [n.d.], (46 pages bd., 49 parts, 5 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 39, Folder 393)
  - Weber "Der Freischutz" Overture. Score and parts for orchestra., Berlin and New York, [n.d.], (90 parts, 11 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 39, Folder 394)
    [Various editions. Publishers include Breitkopf & Hartel and Schlesinger. Many handwritten notes and changes.]
  - Weber "Oberon" Overture. Piano score and parts for orchestra., (8 pages bd., 30 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 39, Folder 395)
  - Weber "Rubezahl" Overture. Parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (35 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 39, Folder 396)
  - Weber Jubel Overture. Score., Schlesinger: Berlin, [n.d.], (49 pages bd. 35 parts) (Box 39, Folder 397)
  - Weber, C.M. "Jagerchor." Vocal score and parts for orchestra. Schlesinger: Berlin, [n.d.], (2 pages bd. 12 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 39, Folder 398)
    [Score includes handwritten addition a.ms. ]
  - Weber, C.M. Jubel Overture. Parts for orchestra, Schlesinger: Berlin, [n.d.], (41 parts) (Box 39, Folder 399)
    [Library catalog identifies the item "First Edition." See also Box 39, Folder 397.]
  - Bach, Johann Sebastian Suite No. 3, D major. Parts for orchestra., Sendff: Leipzig, [n.d.], (24 parts) (Box 39, Folder 400)
  - Dvorak, Anton "Der Bauer ein Schelm" Overture. Scores and parts for orchestra., Simrock: Berlin, 1879, (72 pages bd., 72 pages bd. 45 parts) (Box 39, Folder 401)
  - Haydn, F.J. Symphony B. 55, E flat. "Der Schulmeister." Parts for orchestra., Simrock: Berlin, [n.d.], (25 parts) (Box 39, Folder 402)
  - Rossini "Othello" Overture. Piano score and parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (2 vol. bd., 24 parts) (Box 39, Folder 403)
  - Liszt, Franz Hungarian Rhapsody No. 2. Parts for orchestra., Schuberth & Co.: Leipzig, [n.d.], (47 parts) (Box 39, Folder 404)
  - Liszt, Franz Hungarian Rhapsody No. 6. Score and parts for orchestra. Schuberth: Leipzig, [n.d.], (74 pages bd., 45 parts) (Box 40, Folder 405)
  - Liszt, Franz Hungarian Rhapsody No. 12. Score and parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (49 pages bd. a.ms. fair copy, 39 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 40, Folder 406)
  - Liszt, Franz Hungaria. Score and parts for orchestra., Breitkopf & Hartel: Leipzig, [n.d.], (47 parts) (Box 40, Folder 407)
  - Liszt, Franz "Hunneschlacht (Symphonic Poems).", [n.d.], (45 parts) (Box 40, Folder 408)
  - Liszt, Franz "Tasso" Symphonic Poems. Parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (50 parts) (Box 40, Folder 409)
  - Liszt, Franz "Les Preludes." Parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (48 parts) (Box 40, Folder 410)
  - Liszt, Franz "Ce qu'on entend sur la montagne." Parts for orchestra. [n.d.], (46 parts) (Box 40, Folder 411)
  - Liszt, Franz "Benedictus aus der Kronungs Messe." Score and parts for orchestra. [n.d.], (35 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 40, Folder 412)
  - Liszt, Franz Christmas Oratorio. Score and parts for orchestra., Schuberth & Co.: Leipzig, [n.d.], (22 pages bd. 21 parts, 15 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 40, Folder 413)
  - Liszt, Franz Christmas Oratorio. Parts for orchestra. Schuberth & Co.: New York, [n.d.], (28 parts, 16 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 40, Folder 414)
  - Liszt, Franz Rhapsodie hongroise, No. 2. Parts for orchestra., Leipzig, [n.d.], (43 parts) (Box 40, Folder 415)
  - Liszt, Franz "Annees de Pelerinage," "Anee..Tarantella." Parts for orchestra., Schott's Sohne: Mainz, [n.d.], (44 parts, 1 part a.ms. fair copy) (Box 40, Folder 416)
  - Liszt, Franz "Fest Vorspiel." Score and parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (40 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 40, Folder 417)
  - Scharwenka, Xaver Serenade., [n.d.], (38 parts) (Box 41, Folder 418)
  - Scherz "Der Carnival von Venedig." Parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (38 parts) (Box 41, Folder 419)
  - Schmiedecke Amerikaner Fest Ouverture. Score and parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (46 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 41, Folder 420)
  - Schmelz, Reinhard "Elfenreigen." Parts for orchestra., Schirmer: New York, c. 1890, (42 parts) (Box 41, Folder 421)
  - Schmelz, Reinhard "Traumerei." Scores (2) and parts for string orchestra. Schirmer: New York, c. 1889, (7 pages bd., 4 pages bd. a.ms. fair copy, 24 parts) (Box 41, Folder 422)
  - Schmidt, Richard Concert Overture. Parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (36 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 41, Folder 423)
  - Schmidt, Albert Overture. Parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (36 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 41, Folder 424)
  - Schmidt, Albert Overture. Score., [n.d.], (36 pages a.ms. fair copy) (Box 41, Folder 425)
  - Schneider, Fred Arcana Waltzes, Opus 50. Parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (15 parts ) (Box 41, Folder 426)
  - Schoenefeld, Henry Characteristic Suite, opus 15. Score and parts for string orchestra., Summy: Chicago, c. 1893, (31 pages bd., 24 parts) (Box 41, Folder 427)
  - Zollner, Heinrich "Sommerfahrt." Score., Siegel's: Leipzig, [n.d.], (20 pages bd.) (Box 41, Folder 428)
  - Scholz, Bernhard "Zeitensche Husaren": Opera: Tanz im Lager. Score and parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (27 pages a.ms. fair copy, 40 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 41, Folder 429)
  - Schubert, Franz (Peter) Chorus of the Shepherds. Parts for string orchestra. [n.d.], (5 parts a.ms. fair copy, 4 parts photocopies) (Box 41, Folder 430)
  - Schubert, Franz (Peter) "Ave Maria." Piano score and parts for orchestra., Schlesinger: Berlin, [n.d.], (34 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 41, Folder 431)
  - Schuppe, A. "Trauermarsch." Score and orchestra parts., [n.d.], (34 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 41, Folder 432)
  - Smetana, B. Quartett. Parts for string quartet., Peters: Leipzig, [n.d.], (12 parts) (Box 41, Folder 433)
  - Spicker, Max National Melodies. Score and parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (31 parts a.ms. fair copy, 44 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 41, Folder 434)
  - Spinelli, Niccola A Basso Porto: Prelude. Act III. Parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (42 parts) (Box 41, Folder 435)
  - Spohr, Louis Jessonda Overture. Parts for strings., Peters: Leipzig, [n.d.], (26 parts, 10 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 41, Folder 436)
  - Spohr, Louis Faust Overture. Parts for orchestra. Peters: Leipzig, [n.d.], (30 parts, 4 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 41, Folder 437)
  - Svendsen Rapsodie Norvegienne. Parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (42 parts, 1 part a.ms. fair copy) (Box 42, Folder 438)
  - Svendsen Fest Polonaise. [n.d.], (42 parts, 1 part a.ms. fair copy) (Box 42, Folder 439)
  - Svendsen "Carneval in Paris." Opus 9. Parts for orchestra., Fritzsch: Leipzig, c. 1877, (42 parts, 1 part a.ms. fair copy) (Box 42, Folder 440)
  - Thome, F. "Oeuvres pour Piano." Piano score. Lemoine: Paris, [n.d.], (26 pages bd.) (Box 42, Folder 441)
  - Tombelle, F. de la Suite d'Orchestre. Score and parts for orchestra., Richault: Paris, c. 1892, (30 pages bd., 36 parts ) (Box 42, Folder 442)
  - Thonet, August Scores for four songs: "Studenten Marsch," "Quadrille," "Radfahrer Marsche,", Wein, [n.d.], (14 pages bd. a.ms. fair copy, 24 pages bd. a.ms. fair copy, 12 pages bd. a.ms. fair copy, 33 pages bd. a.ms. fair copy, 10 pages bd.) (Box 42, Folder 443)
  - Verdi Cavatin aus Ernani. Parts for orchestra. [n.d.], (35 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 42, Folder 444)
  - Vierling, Georg Overture "Im Fruhling." Opus 24. Score and parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (33 parts) (Box 42, Folder 445)
  - Vierling, Georg "Der Ramb der Sabinerinnen" Opus 50. Score and parts for orchestra., Leipzig, [n.d.], (60 pages bd., 24 parts) (Box 42, Folder 446)
  - Vieuxtemps Overture Hymne National Belge. Opus 41. Score and parts for orchestra., Schott: Paris, [n.d.], (84 pages bd., 44 parts) (Box 42, Folder 447)
  - Volkmann, Robert Serenaden for string orchestra. Schott's Sohne: Mainz, [n.d.], (32 pages bd., 21 parts ) (Box 42, Folder 448)
  - Vierling, George Overture- Maria Stuart, Opus 14. Parts for orchestra., Schlesinger: Berlin, [n.d.], (25 parts, 10 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 42, Folder 449)
  - Volkmann, Robert Symphony No. 1, Opus 44. Parts for orchestra., Schott's Sohne: Mainz, [n.d.], (46 parts) (Box 42, Folder 450)
  - Gungl "Potpourri." Parts for orchestra. [n.d.], (22 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 42, Folder 451)
  - Heidingsfeld, Ludwig "Zwei Zigeunertanze." Score and parts for orchestra., Hainauer: Breslau, [n.d.], (28 pages bd., 36 parts) (Box 42, Folder 452)
  - Heller, Stephen Praludium und Tarantella. Score and orchestra parts., [n.d.], (24 pages bd. a.ms. fair copy, 25 parts a.ms.fair copy) (Box 42, Folder 453)
  - Hellmsberger, Josef Ball Scene. Parts for orchestra, [n.d.], (19 pages bd, 26 parts) (Box 42, Folder 454)
  - Hellmesberger, Josef Gewitter-Scene, Lewy: Wein, [n.d.], (20 pages bd., 14 parts a.ms. fair copy, 11 parts) (Box 42, Folder 455)
  - Vierling, Georg Overture to Maria Stuart. Score., Schlesinger: Berlin, [n.d.], (64 pages bd.) (Box 43, Folder 456)
  - Hallman Serenade. Score and parts for string orchestra., Breitkopf & Hartel: Leipzig, [n.d.], (4 pages bd., 2 parts, 13 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 43, Folder 457)
  - Hentschel, Theodor "Schone Melusine, Die." Opera-Adagio. Score and parts for orchestra., Oberdorffer: Leipzig, [n.d.], (30 pages bd., 32 pages) (Box 43, Folder 458)
  - Henselt, Adolph "Ave Maria." Parts for orchestra., Oberdorffer: Leipzig, [n.d.], (30 pages bd., 16 pages) (Box 43, Folder 459)
  - Horneman, C.F.E. "Aladdin" Eine Mahrchen-Ouverture." Score and parts for orchestra., Leipzig, 15 February 1868, (80 pages bd., 41 pages) (Box 43, Folder 460)
  - Jvanovici, Joseph "Carmen Sylva Walzer." Parts for orchestra., Oertel: Hannover, [n.d.], (44 parts) (Box 43, Folder 461)
  - Kling, H. Kitchen Concert, opus 445. Piano solo and parts for orchestra., Berlin, [n.d.], (8 pages bd., 40 parts) (Box 43, Folder 462)
  - Kling, H. "Rustic Wedding in Savoy." Parts for orchestra., Oertel: Hannover, (47 parts) (Box 43, Folder 463)
  - Kling, H. Cats Serenade. Violin (direction) score and parts for orchestra. [n.d.], (33 parts) (Box 43, Folder 464)
  - Kolbe, A. Fest Marsch. Score and parts for orchestra., (12 pages bd. a.ms. fair copy, 34 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 43, Folder 465)
  - Kuhlau, Fr. "Elverhoi." Piano score and parts for orchestra. Copenhagen, [n.d.], (40 pages bd., 25 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 43, Folder 466)
  - Berghaus, Karl Muller "Traumkonigs Leib." Parts for orchestra., Hamburg, (20 parts) (Box 43, Folder 467)
  - Berghaus, Karl Muller. Pizzicato Serenade. Parts for orchestra., Hamburg, [n.d.], (26 parts, 3 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 43, Folder 468)
  - Berghaus, Karl Muller "Berceuse." Parts for orchestra., Hamburg, [n.d.], (14 parts) (Box 43, Folder 469)
  - Nehl, Wilh The Caravan. Parts for orchestra., Oertel: Hannover, [n.d.], (37 parts) (Box 43, Folder 470)
  - Neumann, Carl Humoreske, for Trumpet Solo. Parts for orchestra., Oertel: Hannover, [n.d.], (33 parts) (Box 43, Folder 471)
  - Nicosias, Charles "Paroles d'Amour." Parts for strings., Richault & Co.: Paris, 1888, (16 parts) (Box 43, Folder 472)
  - Oelschlegel, A. "With all my heart," Opus 86. Score and parts for orchestra., Schuberth & Co.: New York, 1887, (9 pages bd., 31 parts) (Box 43, Folder 473)
  - Spohr, Louis Recitative and Aria from "Jessonda." Parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (22 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 43, Folder 474)
  - Werkelin, J.B. Marche Orientale. Parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (28 pages bd., 26 parts) (Box 43, Folder 475)
  - Heidingsfeld, Ludwig "Konig Lear," opus 8. Score and parts for orchestra., Hainauer: Breslau, [n.d.], (121 pages bd., 35 parts) (Box 43, Folder 476)
  - Heidingsfeld, Ludwig Zigeunertanze No. 1. Score and parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (20 pages bd. a.ms. fair copy, 21 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 43, Folder 477)
  - Heidingsfeld, Ludwig Zigeunertanze No. 2 Score and parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (21 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 43, Folder 478)
    [See also score in folder 477. ]
  - Spohr, Louis Aria for Jessonda. Score. [n.d.], (32 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 43, Folder 479)
  - Spohr, Louis Symphony No. 3. Opus 78. Parts for orchestra., Schlesinger: Berlin, [n.d.], (20 parts, 10 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 43, Folder 480)
  - Smetana "Wallenstein's Lager." Parts for orchestra., Simrock: Berlin, 1896, (39 parts) (Box 43, Folder 481)
  - Wilheimj, August "All Uncherese" nach Franz Liszt. Parts for violin and orchestra. Schlesinger: Berlin, [n.d.], (26 parts) (Box 44, Folder 482)
  - Weiss, George O. "Militair Marsch." Parts for orchestra., Schuberth & Co.: New York, 1889, (45 parts) (Box 44, Folder 483)
  - Ortega, Aniceto Zaragoza Marsch. Parts for orchestra., Siegel's: Leipzig, [n.d.], (38 parts, 1 part a.ms. fair copy) (Box 44, Folder 484)
  - Oberthur, Charles "Loreley" op. 180. Score., Oertel: Hannover, [n.d.], (43 pages bd.) (Box 44, Folder 485)
  - Wuerst, Richard Variation, op. 50. Score. Bock: Berlin, [n.d.], (24 pages bd.) (Box 44, Folder 486)
  - Urban, Heinrich "Der Rattenfanger von Hameln." Opus 25. Score., Challier & Co.: Berlin, [n.d.], (35 pages bd.) (Box 44, Folder 487)
  - Spohr, Louis Symphony in C. Minor. Score and parts for orchestra., Haslinger: Wien, [n.d.], (31 parts) (Box 44, Folder 488)
  - Spontini, Gaspard Overture from the opera "The Vestal." Piano score and parts for orchestra., Simrock: Bonn; Schlesinger: Berlin, [n.d.], (8 pages bd. 36 parts) (Box 44, Folder 489)
  - Spontini, Gaspard "Olympia Overture." Score and parts for orchestra., Schlesinger: Berlin, [n.d.], (38 parts, 1 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 44, Folder 490)
  - Spontini, Gaspard Cortez Overture. Piano score and parts for orchestra., Schlesinger: Berlin, [n.d.], (11 pages bd., 30 parts, 6 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 44, Folder 491)
  - Tarrow, Miles Marche Solennelle. Score., 1891, (14 pages a.ms.s. fair copy) (Box 44, Folder 492)
    [Signed and inscribed in composer's hand: "To Herr Anton Seidl."]
  - Thonet, August Militar-Musik, Opus 110. Orchestra score. 1891, (14 pages a.ms.s. fair copy) (Box 44, Folder 493)
  - Tombelle, F. de la Orientale. Score and parts for orchestra., Richault: Paris, 1888, (4 pages bd., 16 parts a.ms. fair copy, 12 parts) (Box 44, Folder 494)
  - Werner, August Mignonnette, op. 22. Parts for solo piano and orchestra., Richault: Paris, [n.d.], (27 parts) (Box 44, Folder 495)
  - Taubert, Wilhelm "Liebessliedchen," Op. 134. No. 16. Score and parts for orchestra., Breitkopf & Hartel: Leipzig, [n.d.], (15 pages, 15 parts) (Box 44, Folder 496)
  - Taubert, Wilhelm Geburtstagsmarsch. Op. 146. Parts for orchestra., Bock: Berlin, [n.d.], (36 parts) (Box 44, Folder 497)
  - Taubert, Wilhelm Overture "March." Op. 142. Two scores., Breitkopf & Hartel: Leipzig, [n.d.], (40 pages bd. 47 pages bd. a.ms. ) (Box 44, Folder 498)
  - Taubert, Wilhelm Geburtstagsmarsch, Op. 146. Bock: Berlin, [n.d.], (50 pages bd. ) (Box 44, Folder 499)
  - Taubert, Wilhelm Blaubart Overture. Parts for orchestra., Bock: Berlin, [n.d.], (32 parts) (Box 44, Folder 500)
  - Renz, A. "Das Brausglockhen." Op. 89. Parts for orchestra., Berlin, [n.d.], (17 parts) (Box 44, Folder 501)
  - Zellner, Julius Symphonic. Score for orchestra., Gotthard: Wein, [n.d.], (17 parts) (Box 44, Folder 502)
  - Yradier, J. "La Paloma: Mexikanisches Lied." Score and parts for orchestra., Forbert: Leipzig, [n.d.], (7 pages bd., 31 parts) (Box 44, Folder 503)
  - Wuerst, Richard Ein Marchen. Op. 44. Score and parts for orchestra., Bock: Berlin, [n.d.], (90 pages bd.) (Box 44, Folder 504)
  - Zichy "Story of a Castle." Parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (40 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 44, Folder 505)
  - Wagner, Frederick "Potpourri of American Songs.", Bock: Berlin, March 1846, (4 parts, 40 parts a.m., 1 cover) (Box 44, Folder 506)
  - Wagner, Richard "Traume." Parts for orchestra, Hannover, 27 December 1895, (31 parts, 1 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 45, Folder 507)
    [With handwritten notes. First violin parts with "Direktion." Date taken from fair copy ms.]
  - Wagner, Richard "Traume," Studie zu "Tristan und Isolde." Score and parts for orchestra., Schott's Sohne: Mainz, [n.d.], (5 pages bd., 28 parts) (Box 45, Folder 508)
  - Wagner, Richard "Albumblatt." Parts for orchestra., Fritzsch: Leipzig, [n.d.], (20 parts) (Box 45, Folder 509)
  - Wagner, Richard "Im Treibhaus." Parts for orchestra., Schott's Sohne: Mainz, [n.d.], (10 parts, 9 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 45, Folder 510)
  - Wagner, Richard "Schnezer." Parts for orchestra., Schott's Sohne: Mainz, [n.d.], (12 parts, 9 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 45, Folder 511)
  - Wagner, Richard "Der Ritt der Walkuren." Score and parts for orchestra. Schott's Sohne: Mainz, [n.d.], (17 pages bd., 51 parts) (Box 45, Folder 512)
  - Wagner, Richard "Monolog Act III." Parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (27 parts a.ms. fair copy, 1 cover a.ms. ) (Box 45, Folder 513)
    [With handwritten notes..]
  - Wagner, Richard "Der Engel." Parts for orchestra., Schott's Sohne: Mainz, [n.d.], (10 parts, 9 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 45, Folder 514)
  - Wagner, Richard "Duetto: Fliegende Hollander." Parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (4o pages a.ms. fair copy) (Box 45, Folder 515)
  - Wagner, Richard "Siegfried's Rheinfahrt." Score and parts for orchestra., Schott's Sohne: Mainz, [n.d.], (22 pages bd., 32 parts, 15 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 45, Folder 516)
  - Wagner, Richard "Schluss Scene aus Die Walkure." Parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (45 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 45, Folder 517)
  - Wagner, Richard "Lohengrin." Score and parts for orchestra., Breitkopf & Hartel: Leipzig, [n.d.], (10 pages bd., 25 parts, 7 parts a.ms. fair copy, 6 pages a.ms. fair copy) (Box 45, Folder 518)
    [Second section of ms. marked "Lohengrin: Elsa Entering the Cathedral." ]
  - Wagner, Richard "Siegfried um Walde." Score and parts for orchestra., Schott's Sohne: Mainz, [n.d.], (34 pages bd., 27 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 45, Folder 519)
  - Wagner, Richard "Lohengrin: Prelude." Parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (34 parts, 2 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 45, Folder 520)
  - Wagner, Richard "Parsifal: Vervandlungsmusik." Score and parts for orchestra., Schott's Sohne: Mainz, [n.d.], (61 pages bd., 29 parts ) (Box 45, Folder 521)
  - Wagner, Richard "Schmiedelieder aus Siegfried." Parts for orchestra., Breitkopf & Hartel: New York, [n.d.], (29 pages bd., 39 parts) (Box 45, Folder 522)
  - Wagner, Richard "Gotterdammerung." Parts for orchestra., Schott's Sohne: Mainz, [n.d.], (55 pages bd., 41 parts) (Box 45, Folder 523)
  - Wagner, Richard "Wotan's Abschied und Feuerzauber." Parts for orchestra., Schott's Sohne: Mainz, [n.d.], (37 parts) (Box 46, Folder 524)
  - Wagner, Richard "Das Rheingold: Einzug der Gotter in Walhall." Parts for orchestra., Schott's Sohne: Mainz, [n.d.], (44 parts) (Box 46, Folder 525)
  - Wagner, Richard "Die Meistersinger von Nurnberg." Score and parts for orchestra. Schott's Sohne: Mainz, [n.d.], (33 pages bd., 46 parts, 1 part a.ms. fair copy) (Box 46, Folder 526)
  - Wagner, Richard "Die Meistersinger von Nurnberg." Parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (34 parts) (Box 46, Folder 527)
  - Wagner, Richard "Waldweben." Score and parts for orchestra., Schott's Sohne: Mainz, [n.d.], (42 parts, 2 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 46, Folder 528)
  - Wagner, Richard "Tannhauser." Score and parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (14 pages bd. a.ms. fair copy, 34 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 46, Folder 529)
  - Wagner, Richard "Die Miestersinger von Nurnberg." Score and parts for orchestra., Schott's Sohne: Mainz, [n.d.], (8 pages bd., 30 parts ) (Box 46, Folder 530)
  - Wagner, Richard "Die Miestersinger." Walther's Werbegesang. Score and parts for orchestra., Schott's Sohne: Mainz, [n.d.], (12 pages bd., 32 parts, 2 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 46, Folder 531)
  - Wagner, Richard "Gotterdammerung: Song of the Rhine Daughter." Parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (28 pages a.ms. fair copy) (Box 46, Folder 532)
  - Wagner, Richard "Die Miestersinger: Walther's Preislied." Score and parts for orchestra. Schott's Sohne: Mainz, [n.d.], (12 pages bd., 33 parts, 1 part a.ms.s.) (Box 46, Folder 533)
  - Wagner, Richard "Tannhauser's Pilgrimage, Act III." Parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (39 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 46, Folder 534)
  - Wagner, Richard "Siegfried & Gotterdamerung." Parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (74 parts a.ms. fair copy) (Box 46, Folder 535)
    [Arrangement by Hans Richter.]
  - Bellini "Fantasie: Norma." Parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (33 parts, 1 part a.ms. fair copy) (Box 47, Folder 536)
  - Berlioz, Hector "La Damnation de Faust." Parts for orchestra., [n.d.], (39 parts) (Box 47, Folder 537)
    [With handwritten notes. Housed in five folders.]